<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/resources/master/egSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"
?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title level="m" type="main">Egyptian Gazette</title>
                <title level="m" type="sub">An encoded transcription</title>
                <editor>Your name</editor>
                <principal>Will Hanley</principal>
            </titleStmt>
            <editionStmt>
                <edition>Jacob Amador
                    <date when="2016-10-14">October 14, 2016</date>
                </edition>
            </editionStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>FSU University Libraries</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Tallahassee, FL</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <bibl>
                    <title>Egyptian Gazette</title>
                    <date when="1906-12-18">December 18, 1905</date>
                </bibl>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="page" n="1">
                <head>THE EGYPTIAN GAZETTE</head>
                <head type="sub">No. 7239] ALEXANDRIA, THURSDAY, JULY 13, 1905. [SIX PAGES P.T. 1. </head>
                <div type="section" scope="advertisement"> </div>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="2"> </div>
            <div type="page" n="3"><div type="item">
                <cb n="1"/>
<head>REPRESSION IN RUSSIA </head>              
<head>COURT WITTE’S POLICY.</head>
<head>RAILWAY and postal strike.</head>
<div type="item"> (Gazzette's Special Service.)
    <p>London, Monday, Dec. 18.
Connt Witte i* i o» trying to adopt a so-ere
policy of repreosion The members of the work-
men’n com cil have been arrested.
A railway and postal strike is reported
to-day from St. Petersburg.</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>LOCAL AND GENERAL</head>
<p>To-day’s telegrams.
Reuter’e and Havas’ telegrams will be found
on page 4 i f to day’s issue.
</p>
<p>Training Ship.
The German training-ship 8 ein left Alex-
andria yesterday morning for the Pitseus.</p>
<p>Mouled.
The monied of Sheikh Sale-min El-Pharioi
will be held on the 6ch prox. at Bonlao, Cairo.</p>
<p>Khedivial Club.
'I he fir«t “At H im8” of the sev^n of th •
Cerole Khedivial, Alexandria, will take pUce
at 9.30 p.m. on Welnesli-y next, 20th inst.</p>
<p>Railway Administration.
Autoun B.-y Girgis, thienergetio station-
master of the main Cairo station, has been
promoted to ’he rank of deputy tr .ffi’ madager.</p>
<p>Parade of Troops.
The E.yptian troops in Cairo and the C»det«
of the Military School will parade at the M >-
hamed Aly- qaare on Wednesday next, the
2uth instant, at 8 30 a.m.</p>
<p>Attack on European.
In re’erenoe to our report of an attack by
natives on a Frenohm-n at Alexandria on
Friday we are informed that no oumplaint has
reached the polioe on the subjeot.</p>
<p>Season's Events.
The great ball of the year at Sh-pheard'n
takes place on Jaunary 29. The bal marq-'d et
pondrd at the Gh-zireb Palaoe Hotel is fixed
for Shrove Tueeday (February 27)</p>
<p>Cars in Collision.
Several tram-cars oame into oollision in
Mohame 1 Aly square! Cairo, on Saturday, some
of them bein. derailed and smashed. An om i-
bos, wbichwas passing at the time, oolhded
violently and was shatter, d to pieces. A tram-
driver and two tioke’.-ooileoturs wire injured
by oommg into oontact with the eleotrio wires.</p>
<p>Cadi Sentenced.
Theoouuoil of di-cipline held yesterday a’
tht Ministry of Justice, Cairo, has seuteuo-'d
She'kti Ahmed Abou Khatwa, Cadi of the
Mehkemch dharieh, to be suspended from hi
fanotions tor a period of three m mths, wi hoot
salary, f jr having des’royed an official docu-
ment in the Mehkem.h.</p>
<p>Condign Punishment.
The Arabs who reoontly robbed a European
near Tantah of £1,000 and added inj iry to
theft, have barn sentenced to 15 years’ hard
labour. The affair took plaoe loan tbau six
weeks ago and ihe rapid capture of the robben-
and prqmpt punishment teflaot great oredit on
the Mmistri s of the Interior and of Justice
and ih-ir officials.</p>
<p>Scots School Fellow Workers’ Union.
The sale ot Wvik under the auspices of the
above tooiety was held in St, Andrew’s High
School on Satnrday and was a great sneoese.
Major Allan, of Glasgow, who was accompanied
by his niece, Miss Kerr, performed the open-                
ing ceremony, and in a lew appropriate re-               
marks expres ed tbe pleaaare it gave him to
be present, and the great interest he took i>
the tchools. Miss Rote, in the name ot the
soo'ety, then presented Miss Kerr with a
bouquet. Thereafter the business of the s» eq
was proceeded with, and went on briafry til
6.311, by which hoar all the Btalls had sold off
their ooirtents. The stall-holders and assist-
ants were : Mesdames Buchaian, Gibb, and
Thom, Misses Chevrier, Eiiezir, Hannah,Fran-
ces, Mograbi, Mace, Rcfe, and Saffron. Darin,
the afternoon Mr. 0. Stanley Heatou p ay •
0 gan selections wh ch were much appreoiand
Tbe rooms were leautifody decor.ted wiL
plants aid evergreens kindly aent by Mr-.
Ross, Gordon House.</p></div>
<div type="item"><head>EDEN PALACE HOTEL,</head>
<p>C A I R O.
NOTED FOR ITS EXCKLLKNT CUISINE.
BUBUTBI LIGHT. LIST. -
Special terms for officers of the Army of Occupation and
Government Officials.</p></div>
   
                <div type="item" scope="advertisement">
                    <head>ARISTON AERATED WATERS</head>
                    <p> Guaranteed Distilled.</p>
                    <p> ALEXANDRIA: 7 Rue de la Poste. </p>
                    <p>CAIRO opposite the Tramways Co. Works, Sharia Sahal, Kasr-el-Nil</p>
                </div>
 <div="item"><head>Anglo-American Nile Steamers</head>
 AND
 HOTEL COMPANY
 River Transport of Goods between Alexandria and Cairo.
 THREE SAILINGS A-WEEK
 Agents at Alexandria
 ALEXANDRIA BONDED WAREHOUSE CO. LTD </div>            
                <cb n="2"/>
                <head>YESTERDAY IN ALEXANDRIA.
N0	RENEWAL OF DISTURBANCE
TRIAL OF RIOTERS COMMENCES.</head>
<p>A great deal was witten and said last week
as to what might be expected to occur in the
city yesterday. How far there was any real
ground for alarm must remain a matter of
uncertaintv The certainty is that nothing
whatever of an untoward character happened.
The trial of the natives accused of participation
in the late riot proceeded without anything
more serioas than a good deal of shooting in
the arrest as the vans conveying the prisoners
arrived and departed, and nothing worthy of
note took place in Rosetta street</p>
<p>The authorities are to be commended for the
very effective precautions taken against a
further riotous outbreak. Mounted polioe pa-
trolled the low quarters of the town, and the
latest attempt at riot wonld have been suppressed
before it could have attained any serions
proportions. But so quiet was every neighbor-
hood, that a stranger unaware of the history of
he last few days would have wondered what
the extra display of force meant. We trust
that this state of things may continue and
that the rowdyism that has been, unfortun-
ately, so rife among the lower classes, both
European and native, may have received a
check that will prove effective in the future.</p>
<p>The trial of the persons implicated in the
disturbances of Sunday week took plaoe yes-
terday morning, in the Native Court. Rosetta-
street The court was prodded over by Abl
El	Megid Bey Fend, and Mahfonz Bey
represented the Parquet, Hopkinson Bey,
Morice Bey, and Haddaya Bey being present
The number of the accused, brought into
he court was 104. In the court-yard a crowd
of about 200 natives had gathered, and 40
policemen were on duty.</p>
<p>At half-past eleven the president of the
Parquet began his speech for the prosecution,
naming the persons suspected of rioting. After
giving particulars of the charge against 60 or
7O prisoners, Mahtouz Bey asked the Court to
allow 5 minuter respite, and this was granted.
On resuming, Mahfeuz Bey contnued reading
the long list of accused, making comments as
he went on. When the reading of the list had
been concluded, the president of ihe Patquet
addressed the judge somewhat as follows;—</p>
<p>"I trust you are not surprised at the
spectacle of 104 persons under trial, as the
mob that took part in the disturbance of Sun-
day afternoon, of which these persons formed
part, numbered 15,000 individuals. Indeed,
we had not a sufficient number of police to
arrest every one who took part in the distur-
bance, and that is why the Fire Brigade was re-
quisitioned to disperse the thousands of people.
Therefore we cannot particularise the circum-
stances of the event so far as to report what
each of the rioters did. It was some what
impossible to do so in such a wide-spread
disturbanoe. We arrested 400 and after
inquiry have discharged 1 half that number. The
other haif, i e., the 200 prisoners, were seen
by the police and the sheikhs of the quarters
to be making a disturbauoe. Had there been
witnesses to prove that the other 200 or part
of them had taken part in the troubles we
should of course have kept them to be
tried. Had this disturbance taken plaoe
15 years ago the Court would probably
not have found an article in the Penal Code
applicable to the present case, for it is only 15
years since Articles 220 and 221 were added
to the code, owing to a similar incedent which
took place at that time... In short, we have
brought these people before you in the hope
that they will receive severe punishment to
prevent furhter public disturbances. The case
was first in the hands of the police, and it then
passed into those of the Parquet, and now, the
enquiry being oompiete I, beg to lay the case
in your hands,trusting you will bear the respon-
sibility of giving the proper judgment.”</p>
<p>At the conclusion of the speech for the pro-
secution, some discussion took plaoe as to the
defence of the prisoners, and finally the hearing
was adjourned till next Saturday.
The trial of the second batch of 71 prisoners
took place this morning in the same Court, and
was still proceeding as we went to press.</p></div>

   <div type="item">   <head>WAR OFFICE GAZETTE.</head>
<p>Lieutenant A. E. King, Royal Garrison Artil-
lery, having reported his arrival in Egypt from
Bng and, is take * on the strength of the E.yp
from the 1st October, 19o5, with
the rank of Bimbashi. This officer is posted
to the Artillery, and appointed Ordnance
Officer.</p>
<p>L eutenant J. G. E. Craik, Seaforth High
landers, having reported his arrival in Egypt
from England, is taken on the strength of the
Egyptian Army, from the 23rd November,
1905, with the rank of Bimbashi This officer is
posted to the 3rd Battalion.</p>
<p>Lieutenant O. L Smith, v.c., the Duke of
Cornwall’s Light Infantry, having reported his
arrival in Egypt from Gibraltar, is taken on
the strength of the Egyptian Army, from 1st
December, 1905, with the rank of Bimbashi.
This  officer is pasted to the 2nd Battalion.</p>
<p>El Bimbashi C. Leigh, D.S.O., Staff Officer,
Khartoum District, to be Local Karmakam,
whilst Acting Officer Commanding, 4th
Bitalion To date 10-19-05.</p></div>
MCR S HOTEL, Encampment
OH 1,KK .V (KRIS
Ih OoNNBCTXuH with 1HS Kahoqh Hqtei,
Fatool
For pgrtloalM* Apply Ur. TABOO, Fajroiua
                <cb n="3"/>
<head> THE CITY ELECTION.</head>
<head>THREE-CORNERED CONTEST.</head>
<head>GOVERNMENT APPOINTMENTS.
</head>
<head>(Gazette’s Special Service.)</head>
<p> London, Monday, Dec. 18.
In regard to the election of a member for the
City, Sir E. Clarke has not yet withdrawn in
favor of Lord Carton, and a three-cornered
contest is therefore probable.</p>
<p>Further Government appointments are to be
announced to-morrow.</p>
<div type= "item"><head>COUNCIL OF MINISTERS.</head>
<p>The Council of Ministers met this morning
under the presidency of H.H the Khedive and
formally authorised the constriction of the
Banah Barrage.</p>
<p>Several decrees, referring to the expro-
priation of land for purposes of pnblio utility,
were also sigred.</p></div>
<div="item"><head>POST CARD FACILITIES.</head>
<head>NEW REGULATON.</head>
<p>The regulations probib frog piotnre po-t
jatdj to and from plaoes abroad from bearing
\ communication on the left half of the
address side have been relaxed so far as the
Egyptian Post Office is con'ierned. 8" oh cards
will henoeforth be aooepted at postoard rates
for transmission to Austria. Belgium, Den-
mark, Franoe, Germany, Holland, Hungary,
Laly, Lnx“mbnrg, Mexico, Norway, Portugal,
R saia, Sweden, 8 wit* -rland, Tunis, and the
United Kingdom,</p></div>
<div="item"><head>EXTENSION OF PENNY POSTAGE</head>.
<p>Penny postage between the Straits Settle-
ments and Egypt and the Sudan will come
into force on the 1st January next, when
letters from the Straits Settlements may be
sent to this country or the Sudan for one
penny, and letters from Egypt and the Sudan
to the Settlements for five milliéme'</p></div>.
<div="item"><head>GREEK LOAN.</head>
<p>According to the “Levant Herald,” the
3reek Patriarchate of Jerusalem having failed
0 conclude a loan with the Natio al Bank of
Jreeoe, Mgr. Damianos, Pa' riarch • f J-rmaLm
las requested ’he Patriarch of Alexandria *o
approach th - Greek fiua oiers in Egypt on tt q
mbjeot.</p></div>
<div="item"><head>TRADE'PROSPECTS WITH
ABYSSINIA.</head>
<p>The Berlin correspondent of the "Daily 
Chronicle" telegraphs as follows:-"The treaty
of commerce and friendship between Germany 
and Abyasinia will be presented to the Rech-
stag in a few days. The Minister of the Inte-
rior is laboriously preparing a list of articles
(for use in German Chambers of Commerce) in
demand in Abyasinia. Through Abyasin a Ger-
many hopes to open up  large caravan trade
with Southern Sudan and the Interior of Africa</p></div>
-- ~
<div="item"><head>THE SUCRERIES.</head>
<p>The fif'h meeting of the creditors of the
3 cidte desSuoreVies et de laR.Smeried’Bgypte
look place on Saturday at 8 p.m. Proceedings
were brief and to the point. After Me. Ferrate
bad appeared in the name of new creditors Me.
Carton de Wiart stated that the administra-
tive board h«d oome to an agreement over the
oonditione of the arrangement, hot that a |
telegram from Paris h g red that the text • f he ■
proposals should not be given to the conrt till
after Tuesday's meeting of the shareho'ders.
Therefore, could the leaned judge postpone
the hearing till Tharedey t Bnt Judge Took
ooold not; h * had bad delays enough and would
not eat bin wordsoi the last meeting. On Satur-
day next a vote would be given on the propo-
sals and the affiir would go before the
Tribunal. Any rew postponements must be
. Tinted by" that body, he would rtfase the
responsihili'y. So on Satrd-y nextr.be Com-
mercial Tribunal < f th“ Mixed I’o ut ake-i up
the oase if any more delays ooour.</p></div>
<head>ROADS IN EGYPT.</head>
<p>For several years now, read construction in
Egypt basbeen suspended, except upon a very
limited soale, in oonsequenoe of the imp wsibi-
lity of finding funds wherewith to maintain
these roads, when oompletod, bat, in the budget
for 1905, a sum of LE. 10,000 was allot-
ted for this purpose, and road construction ;
may in future be expeotod to show considerable ,
anuoal progress. The denunjs (or new roac\s
are steadily increasing, and the people fully
..niiraoiai* ihaadvan ages g ift ed by e*-y com-
munloa’ions,</p>
<p>In Assiout Provi o\ a programme for e’fbt
new roads has been approve i by the Ppinooial
Council, and Work has been commenced
In Mimeh a similar pr or.ogme is under
oonsideratii q, while the Pro* me of Qhirgheh
has voted a mm of LE 18,000 for the oon-
(trnotion of four sow roods,	'</p>
                <cb n="4"/>
<head>SUEZ CANAL COLLISION.</head>
<head>JUDGMENT IN CHATHAM CASE</head>.
<head>CLAN CUMMING HELD RESPONSIBLE.</head>
<div="item"><p>Sir Gorell Barnes and Trinity Masters, in
die Admiralty Conrt, on Satnrday we k,
joncloded the hearing of the oase of the owners
if the Chatham and her crew, suing for loss of
fffeotH, v. the owners i f the Clan Camming
ind freight. Tbi« was a claim and oonnter-
ilaim for damages, owing to a oollision which
xoarred between the two vessels in the Suez
Banal on September 5 last, resulting in the
linking of the Chatham, whioh oanght fire.
3he wau laden wittyi cargo of 180,' OOlbs. of
iyuamite, and 160,600 detonators. The sink-
ing of the Chatham leenlted in blocking the
Muial traffic for a few days, until, by order of
tbeqanal authorities, the vessel was blown np.
The aotiou now came before the court for a
ieoision as to whioh of the two vessels was to
blame for the oollision.</p></div>
<p>Iu giving judgment his Lordship said that in
irder to appreciate the oollision it was ne-
sestary to tee how these vessels were aproaoh-
ing eaoh othur. Ac the part of the canal where
the oollisii-n oconned, vessels proosediug
louihwaid had to ‘ tie np” to posts whenever it
was neoessaiy for steamers to past np. His
Lordship then deait with the rales applying to
lse of the searoh-iight and other lighta whioh
iad beeu laid down, m the canal regulations,
i’he southern-going vessel must show the
iniliant light till ftie pat into the siding, and
iben give tbe ordinary light to show she had
;ot iheie. A vessel under enoh oiroumsianoea
nuat aot reasonably wheu going south, while
!id one going north must watoh and see she
lid not get too near the other ship. He thought
hat, having regard to the impossiuiiity ot
>eiug certain ot the distanoe separating two
rcss- Is under these oiroomstanoes, it wa»
ibsolutely necessary for tbe vessel going north-
vt>r l to keep herself well in hand, so that she
vas oowpletely prepared to deal with any
iveutuaheiei she jmght meet from the rhip
ouuing south. Sir Gorell Barnes pcin ei out
hat each side argued that the other
res el had acted in an unreasonable mau-
ler, and it was therefore neoe>sary to see
vbat really did happen. He had no donbt
hat the Chatham was at the time of the oolli-
ion practically a stationary ship, and had
toted in precisely tin same manner as the had
io ed on two previous occasions, wheu she had
Irawn up to allow three other vessels to psms.
Phe rest of the oa»e was somewhat simple,
ieoan«e the collision was a severe ooe, the
Han Camming offttug, as she did, right into
he bows of the Chatham as iar as the windlass.
Phe oely other question was to examine
rbe her the Clan Cumining bed proceeded
nth proper and reasonable precaution. In his
ipmion, and that of the Elder Brethren, those
n oharge of the defendanta’ ship did not aot
essonably in approach ng the Cuatham, having
igued to the ludiQations given to them. The
blame for the collision rested solely on the bad
lavigation of the Clan Camming, and she must
ie louud alone to blame for the oollision.</p>
<p>After some little argument the question as
o whether the ship was properly blown up was
aft for farther oousideration.</p>
<div="item"><head>THE JUDICIAL ADVISER</head>
<p>The Judicial Adviser arrived atKenehyes-
erday and attended the hearing ot some
nmioal oases in the Assize Court of that tow r
n n 1 ........</p></div>
<div="item"><head>AN ALEXANDRIAN ANALOGY.</head>
T<p>he United 8tates Government has followed
he example set by British military anthpritiee
vhen they passed troops through Egypt daring
he Crimean War. A few days ago a detaohment
torn the U.8. oroiser Minneapolis passed
hroogh Benia in p ain clothes, bound for
he defence of the Embassy in Petersburg.
Baring the CritBeah Wary when British
lavalry brigades were mostly represent-
'd by casualties, after Balaclava, the 10th
lussars were fetched from {ndiiy and loaned;
hroogh Egypt inqivilian guise, to take i-hip*
igaln at Alexandria, It tie a good way off,
hen, from the Canal, and the authorities had
to ohoioe bnt to bring the regiment along in
his Wh > ly unprecedented fashion,</p></div>
<div="item"><head>STEAMER MOVEMENTS</head>
<p>The Mo s liner Amasis sailed this momiog
for Liverpool, vii Malta, with pesseagert,
mails, and general oargo, including 4,884 bales
tottoii, **	'tm*- >	'9	v</p></div>
                <cb n="5"/>
<head>THE CAIRO KUTTABS.</head>
<head>DISTRIBUTION OF GRANTS IN-AID.</head>
<head>SPEECH BY H. E. THE MINISTER.</head>

<p><div="item">The distribution of the grants-in-aid to the
finis and arifii of the Cairo kattaba took plaoe
yesterday morning at 10 o’olook,in the amphi-
theatre of the examination \ halls of the Minis-
tiy of Pnbiio lus motion, Darb-el Gamam’z,
Cairo, under the preaideuoy of H.E. the Min-
ister of Pnbiio luatruotiou, and in the presence
of Yaoonb Artin Pasha, Abd-el-Haiim Pasha
Assem, Mustapha Pat,ha Maher, Ismail Pasha
Abbza, and Mr. Dunlop.
Ihe proceedings oommenotd by a rsoital of
one of the Suras of the Koran. Sheikh Mo-
homed ihen£ inspector of Knttabs, then
made a speech explaining the objeots of the
grant-in-aid scheme aoddeaonbing the progress
that had been rta.ioed.
The grauts-iu-aid were then distributed, and
HE. the Mmister of Pnbiio Instruction, in
Closing the prooeeUi igs, Delivered a speech
exhorting the fikiB to wnoie-hearied devotion
to their oailiug.
The following is a Frenoh translation of the
speech of the H.E. the Minister of Pnbiio
Instruction :—
Lt statuuque qni vient d’fitre prdsentoe et
le* snbvenuous que l’on vient de dieinbuer
sunt le pins Eloquent disoonrs q .’on pause
proLoaucr on dome sur le sojet qui nous
uooupe. Biles pronvent a’une maiudra dvidente
I’inidrdt quo lea Egyptians pienneut 41’iiutruo-
tion et a l’danuatiou de leors enfant*, et la
confianoe qu’ds one en vous, confianoe k la
quelle Tons dovez rdpoudre eu traitanv la> en-
fant* oonuue nu Don pbre traits sas prupre*
eefanta ; elles prouvenc auosi que les uuti o-
touts meritent d’6 re loud* pour iezd.e qn’ns
ontapportdi I’aocoaiplissement de leur tithe.
II est a aspdrer que vous forez to us voe efforts
pour vous perieo.iouner et pour aa.d.M>rer ia
aituatiou de vos Kouttaba, afin as mdiiter •
,’avenir des rdoompenses enoore plus ioiportan-
tes que oel,e^ que vous avts‘'rt;ue* jutqu’a ot
jour.</div></p>

<div="item"><head>INSPECTOR FOR SINAI.</head>
<p>Mr. Brantley has been appointed inspector
for the Sinai Peninsula of the War Office, with
the powers ot an inspector uncer the MinLtr>
of the Iuterior. Mr. Brantley's knowledge of
the Bedouins of Egypt and the Sudan is re-
markable, and the appointment ia one which
inquires snob know.edge in the offio.ai to whom
n is given.</p></div>

<div="item"><head>IMPORTANT FIND OF PAPYRI</head>
<p>Ou behalf of the Bodlean Library, Mr.
Offutd has seonied a somewhat large ooileotion
of fragmentary Haorew and Aramaio mano-
senpto which it u to be hoped, when oarefnlly
examined by the Oxford paleographers, will
prove not oniy important, but perhaps oom-
piete some of ihe portions of oodioeo already
at Ox ord or Camonuge. So few papyri, or
manuscripts, now reaoh Cairo because agents
of European museums travel into the Egyptian
provuioes to obtain them from the frUaheen,
that it is fortunate that this series of duon
menta has been found oomparatively intact.</p></div>

<div="item"><head>GEHEZIREH PALACE</head>
<p>-Theto w re several lun- hi-on parties given
at the Gbez reh Palaoe Hotel yesterday. Mr.
Viliemorin, first seoretary of the Frenoh
Embassy, had a party of twelve, including M.
and Mine d* 1a Boalitndre, Count and Conntass
dc Sarionne, and Marquis Sglvaga-Raggi.
Sir Hugh and Lady Sttilty were entertaining
friends, as ilso were Lady Sampson, Mrs.
Harrison, and Mrs. George Pauling. Many
peoi le gathered for tea in the verandah daring
the afternoon. From to-day (December 18) tbe
Tz gane Band will play there every afternoon
from 4-6 on the ve audah, and also every even-
ing daring and after dinner.</p></div>

<div="item"><head>HELOUAN WATER SERVICE.</head>
<p>In 10 yean the amount of water supplied to
private piraons at Hrhraaq Has more than
doubled. TTie receipts from private oonsumeM
were LE. ^95 last year in exoern of the
previous year. An ample supply of water has
been kept np throughout ’he iffiole yeer. Tbg,
total grons profit for the year amonnts to
L.R 3,('53.617. A sum of LK 606 figures as
extraordinary expenditure. Of tbie>nm L.B.
810 was spent for oast-iron pipes, valves, eta,
LB. 107 for new Frager water m tres, and
LR 190 for transport from Gh seh and ereethm
of two 65 H.P. Lancashire boilers. Tbe ereotion
of these (which an practically as good as new)
gives a large steam reserve for many years
to oome. 410 lin. mc’ros of 30 o/m. pipes have
been laid from the town to the reservoir to
■epieee the 15 cfm. pipes on main delivery
from pumps. All oorroded tad small diatpeter
pipes have now been removed and replaced ’Dy
new ones. This completes the work bn the
maib delivery. Qreat dissatisfaction exists in
Hefonau h oause »e tneasons h we been taken
m yet to supply the town with filtered w-ter.
The oo-t would pot be gnat, as a complete ‘
sandrfil.ter plant; similar to the one in Ghiseb,
ooold be put np for L R 5. 0«', or amaohanioal
filter plant for LJ V» O. Mr.Ourtis estimates
that the oost of water webfeifa flushing pipes,
and oontinnal cleaning of mnd from the
foyrohn, would be sufficient to pay 8% per
tafitub oh the cost oi the tttm,</p></div>
                <cb n="6"/>
<head>SAVOY SMALL DANCE</head>
<head>THE FIRST OF THE SEASON</head>.
<head>LARGE GATHERING OF CAIRO SOCIETY</head>
<div="item"><p>The Savoy Hotel has a great reputation, and
the entertainment provided ab Saturday even-
ing will be hard to beat. Tbe invitations to
the fi st small danoe of the season brought
the whole of Cairo society together, -and th*
Applications for dinners were so numerous
that the management found it nonne-iy to
atilise the adjoining private dining-rooms
as well as the tent arranged as a winter
garden.</p>
<p>Amongst those giving dinnerparties wen:—
Col. and Mrs. Patterson Bey, with a party
of ten, inolndiag Miles de VilleboU, Mr.
and Mn. Stout, etc.; the Hon. F. G. Morgen
with seven guests, including CoL and Mrs.
Matohctt, Mr. and the Hon. Mrs,; ffn—f,
e a ; Mr. and Mrs. Charles Boyle; with Mrs.
G orge Boyle and Capt and Mm. MoLean ;
Si> Charles So -tter, who entertained
Pa-ha Pehmy and his lamily. Among others
dining were Baron von Opponheiin, Dr. Tribe
and party, Marqnis de Pijravanti, .Major
Davidson and party, M. and Mme Friedman
and party, Mr. Lombard and party, Mr.
Paxton and party, M. de Bdinski and party,
Mrs. Lyman and party, Mr. and Mm.
Porter, eta, eta</p>
<p>The big dining-hall, with to exoeltent floor,
was reserved for dancing, and by eleven
o’clock that and ths halls and ■«i~'m were
fit ed by a fashionable throng. Many nfSftrs
of both the Army of Occupation and the
Egypt an Army were promt, end the band
supplied by Maestro Braoale kept people
•lancing till the email hours, whan there was
* general adjournment to the reetanrant for
■upper.</p>
<p>Vary many pretty droesw were to beseen, per-
haps none.prettier than that of Mrs. Soott-
Da gleiah, woo was universally admired in her
pate blue chiffon diamante, with many ru filings
interspersed with oream roses at the hem, and
a wreath of the same flowers over her shoulders.
Mis. Charles noyle was in biaok, aud Mm.
MoUan was also in biaok, with mnoh jet on
.he bodioe and topee of jet forming the top
part ot her eieevee. Mrs. George Ruyla was
wearing a charming soft white msslin «PMHted
with cream guipure and overlaid with floral
pray of fiimy biaok. At the rUwillaifff and
-leaves and hem were many ruohings of soft
biaok-edged gauze ribbon, and Utah velvet
bows witn long diamond hackles Were on the
bodioe terminating in long sash ends. Mm.
Rom was in gold oh ffon valours, wide inser-
tions of lace embroidered in golden passe-
manterie eoeiraling the skirt aod forming the
upper part of the eorsaga Mrs. Porter, one of
< nr n.w residents, was ia white with mnoh
aoe aud a deep draped oorselet. The Misroe
Boliook ware drosaed alike in eteam net with
folded oerotures and bows of pale Mae. Mm.
Stoat had a lovely lace drees, the skirt with a
doable floanoe adorned with appliqufe of
Pompadeur pmk roses; the bodice, made with
a small ba que, was also heavily appUqod
with the roees.</p></div>
<div="item"><head>PERSONAL AND SOCIAL</head> 
<p>A farewell dinner was given at the Savoy' I
Restaurant last evening in honour of CoL I
Friend, who is leaving Egypt hnmbdiately. I
Thof-e present were Lord Celril Pasha, Mr. I
Satow, Col. J. K. Watson, Capt Lyons, Mr. I
Crawley, M«jor Dalavoye, Mr. Astley Friend, I
Mr. Watson, Capt Bigge, Mr. A.H. Ptary, Mr. I
Geville, Mr. C. Clifton. Mr. L Reid, Gapt I
Gillson, Capt Faylay, Capt MoMurdo, Mr. I
Graham, Mr. Richmond, Capt. Protheroe I
Smith.</p></div>	—	I
<div="item"><p>Major Dunegan, who met with a hasty I
aooi’ent on Gnesireh racecourse on Tuesday I
last when his home fell while galloping on the I
t-aok, is progree>»g as well as can be expected, I
bnt it is feared *h»t his injury will interfere I
wiihhis reiumiug duty for some tune.</p></div>	
<div="item"><p>It is probable that Mgjdopa Wfaitehoure, I
who has been a stranger tyKjypt for the last
few years, will pay as a^ visit this season.</p></div>	
<div="item"><p>Mrs. Farrar, Mim Nelly Farrar, Mm*Farrar, I
and Mim Stuart left Mena Hotue Hotel I
yesteiday for a trip np the Nila Mrs. Farrar I
and her family will return to Mena House H
Hotel in the first week of Marta.</p></div>
<div="item"><p>Mr Rmeet Hill and Miur Wynne Roberts, 1
from Rodleaf, Penghurst, arrived at Mena 1
House Hotel a few days ago for a short stay.</p></div>
<div="item"><p>Mr. Henry Simpson, the well-known artist,
who has been staying at the Savoy Hotel, 1
Luxor, left for Assouan a few days ago.</p></div>
<div="item"><p>The latest arrivals at the Savoy Hotel,
Luxor,, include Baron and Baroness von
B ittler, Mir Henry Mosier and party, Mr. R. I
Campbell Thompson, Mr. A. Wi Woodman 1
Dondio, M. D., Mr. Nepit F. Tabet, Mr. Jelius
Tun dor, Mr. Hans Trier.</p></div>	
<div="item"><p>The following are the pmeengem by the P.S. I
Prinee ABImm, which left StaUal yesterday 1
Mrs. LaiJlaw, Hon. FionMe Heneegft Sir	I
Vesey and Lady Strong, Misses BartnoO, lb. 1
F. HOI, Mr- Leotard S. Tyler, Mr. Edward I
Kirkham, Mm, E. MoClean, Mim Greg, Mm, I
Attwood Mattbeim, Mr. J. If, fw,</p></div>	|

                
                
                
                
                
                
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="4">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="5">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
            <div type="page" n="6">
                <cb n="1"/>
                <cb n="2"/>
                <cb n="3"/>
                <cb n="4"/>
                <cb n="5"/>
                <cb n="6"/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
